all right hello YouTube and Facebook we
are alive eyes welcome to today's
project roundtable there it's three of
us so far
jublia is out today really wish we had
some kind of a steady agenda
I do remember okay so the typical way
that this flows isn't we each sort of go
around and say where things are at
what's changed since last time what
we're working on and then after that we
can talk about you know anything that
one of us is sort of having issues with
it maybe we want to bounce off the
others so did one of you who won your
horse I usually all right person so
my project is
wiki election that has been going okay
but focusing a little bit more over the
last two weeks on this on you know DMV
projects on together tech whatever it's
being called and yesterday we actually
did a session on showing off the
prototype for project tracker just don't
show the online profiles and work that's
earnest help that's needed that kind of
thing I had been working on the specs
for wiki election my goal is in the next
I'd say a week or two to start having
someone actually start to code the
really really early version of it just
so I can actually start having a real
thing online because it can be hard to
conceptualize and going forward with the
weekly live streams I actually have some
one possibly two people attending today
which will be nice I think that's about
it for work election
okay so as opposed to the previous
update I made last week which was about
this little webpage designed to schedule
meetings there is another project I've
been working on so past many years
actually it's like a pet project of mine
and it started as an attempt to map all
the people organizations projects and
everything it seems like everyone does
it actually I heard about at least three
or four senior projects even in space
but my idea was a sort of cross between
project management software and a
database and actually last week I was
able to get it to the point where I can
not only speak of what it is and how I
see it I think I am now able to actually
show it and it's very early prototype
but I think that shows what what can
happen in this project so what I need at
this point for someone to tell me if
it's really it would make sense or not
if it's a same idea or not and basically
as you discussed in one of the earliest
meetings about how to proceed with
propositions of projects it would be
good for someone to talk holes in my
idea because I had this idea for so long
that I can no longer tell if it's valid
or not right so I need someone to
actually go and yeah this doesn't make
sense because oh it does make sense and
you know at this stage I just I very
really appreciate to some information
and feedback about where I should go
next with this because my choice is
either to start a Kickstarter campaign
maybe like this because it would be very
good
obviously if it was sustainable enough
for me to work exclusively on this and
if not well what to do about about it in
in the future it is going to be useful
or not that's a bit cool yeah I think
that sounds like something to revisit
that's what we're all we've all given
her updates just up there alright Brad
or Shiloh most IANA I can go really
quick I don't really have can you guys
hear me okay yep I don't really have a
project that I'm working on but I do
have a pet project that's been going on
for a long time and it's a tracking idea
as well so I'd love to hear more about
your pet project so that'll be good and
I did want to mention that I missed
yesterday's call while you were going
over the hmm I don't know it's a website
that you made for the project the
projects I did check it out and I
thought it was pretty good and I love
that you can just easily click on links
to go to different websites to get more
information so cool thank you and if you
have even just a pet project you can
feel free to sign up and it's a seven
your own stuff or you know sign up to
help with other things yeah I'd like to
see more like I like this idea of
together tag and actually building it
together so I'd like to gift hearing
what else is out there that's similar
and maybe just adding to it and not
really needing to hold my own project
right yeah I think that's going to be a
pretty useful part if we can actually
get you know number two people won't
like we lost Brett some issues I'm
seeing some setting switch on these a
box here
Brad you can use the private chat to
chat to us if you're having any audio
issues or anything to give that a second
because I'm guessing you showed up he
wants to talk about his project
okay so this happens audio-video issues
we get from the whole a moment how did
the meeting go yesterday did you have
any new things worked out about that
project oh nothing really
anything specific came out of it was
more just a demo of it so that the
people who are currently demoing it can
sort of go in there and do a bit better
test run with their projects like I
think he was gonna add something to help
need it and like Julie was gonna add
some events for the various projects so
we can start to have you know some of
the the events filled out start to have
some help needed I wonder if adding well
this might not be this right place but
I'm still struggling to understand the
schedule so there's just a variety of
things and I can't necessary I'm like
how am I going to be any help in that
meeting or not so sometimes like and
I've been really busy too it's like
everybody has a little more time right
now but right I'm home and have these
drop hoops jobs going on and it's very
disruptive fair enough yeah a lot of
people have used this time off to get
even more busy and like yeah it's just
new projects and like I I work from home
for years and I work for a big company
that has people all over the world but
most of them don't work from home and
now that they do you can tell they all
had these side projects in mine for a
long time and so now that all we reach
out it's so nice to finish a project at
home it's just so rewarding and that's
actually the answer to the question
about you know when you don't have to
work what is it that you're going to be
doing because some people that's to
think that if you have no job as such
you know you're going to be bored and
start drinking and baby you know and the
answer to that is obviously there is so
much you can do and so much you would be
doing if you didn't that work yeah yeah
and I'm sure like five or ten percent of
people might not do
something if you don't given the chance
that's fine by me
I'm not sure I want to work with
somebody that doesn't want to work
anyway you know it's I expect some most
I don't know people to take a year or
two of unwinding right I mean that's
after a long period of doing a job to
just sustain existence you will need
some time to not do anything and to feel
that you don't have to do anything in
order to start thinking about what it is
you really want to be doing yeah all
right so it sounds like Brad won't be
able to rejoin he's having some ongoing
technical issues so I guess we can say
that the first part is done so if we
want to dive into sort of your ask dip
matheus message if you want to explain a
bit more about the help that you're
looking for on your project and sort of
like if it's online also even where it
is what kind of feedback you're after
that's what it first first of all a
little bit curious right now because mmm
I saw well there's your project about
list of projects for that generally can
be this is a list of projects in Granby
space that's the short description but
so I know
mark has an idea of his own then there
is James who I think working on
something similar then there was a
discussion about fractal organizations
with the oh sorry I know which is the
Terran which is the
working on a halo and I think this is
like very similar thing that differences
in details but I think it converges at a
design point you need to you have to
have a list of a map of what's out there
and it means both projects but because
projects are not something on their own
they are grounded in real problems
it was first due to the problem and then
you create projects to deal with the
problem and similarly with organizations
I think it makes more sense to identify
a problem and create a team entity of
nothing to deal with this particular
thing instead of and I've been thinking
about it for the past couple of days as
well the difference between game a and
game B the staffing like in game a you
create a company or organization and you
have something and then you look for
problems and possibly do I know profits
for this entity who created and instead
maybe the point of attention should be
should start with okay this is the
problem like like we need to provide
blueprints for a vertical hydroponic
farm this is the real real problem and
solution to that is going to be very
useful for like everyone in the world
then you create a team which produces
the schematics of blueprint of something
instruction how to be able to this open
source set and then it's done and then
you can dissolve the team so I think
this is similar to idea to the fractal
organizations
teams are created when they are needed
and they can be dissolved when they
cease to be needed they dumb purpose and
then like so okay so my question
Magnusson question was how do we deal
with the situation where we have four
very similar projects okay good question
I'm actually in the same boat somewhat
on the together
sorry on the wiki election side cuz
Bentley had reason score one of the
things that we're talking about is in
together tech right you can definitely
still you know join or be a part of it
if there's you know four different
projects that are kind of doing a
similar thing and this is one of the
areas where we want to explore is this
is typically an area where in game a you
would be competitors and you wouldn't
talk to each other you know you would
have that sort of a thing going and I
think there still be a bit of rivalry
just you know as egos get involved and
people are attached to there probably
nicely but one of the concepts that
we've talked about is having something
called a co-op Council where as you take
groups of people who sort of in theory
are in competition and you create some
kind of a council to say hey you know
here's four different theories for how
we're gonna solve this problem and then
you know possibly meet weekly or monthly
bounce ideas off let's say what worked
and what didn't work is in the end I'm
trying to solve Miss information with
wiki election if I join forces or you
know like somewhat with two or three
people and one of them ends up solving
it still solved and if you know I
learned some things to help them along
the way that's fine by me so that's a
part of it that being said as far as I
know that book is unwritten like I think
we're sort of talking about ways that we
think that you know you might be able to
talk about this game B I'm not aware of
any existing methodologies or something
for this so I think it's just starting
it and seeing what we learn and you know
how we step on each other's toes and how
we can help each other and that kind of
thing yeah exactly
I feel this
means similar kind in different
companies I worked for even if even
within the same company
which in theory is you have competition
between companies but there shouldn't be
no competition inside you still on all
levels yeah besides but it seems like
each entity was created be it a company
or Department we seen a company or even
team a team B team C once you have this
not sure how to call it
once you have this entity consisting of
more than one person and in some cases
it's enough to have two people in order
to start some sort of competition
because egos and you know my project is
obviously better because it's my yeah so
it happens all over the place and even
in environments where by definition
should be non-competitive there is still
eager involved and stuff happens and not
everyone is happy to work for the
greater greater purpose like when you
think about cathedrals people who build
cathedrals
they didn't even they knew the
cathedrals were not going to be built we
see in their lifetimes they didn't care
if that there is any competition there
was no competition there was the
blueprint and they just realized that
for like 300 years which is awesome and
scary at the same time because it seems
we cannot do this anymore
right yeah it's like that I'm gonna
butcher this proverb but the whole thing
like you know it shows the quality of
someone or something if they plant trees
whose shade they'll never sit in that's
what doing work then you're not going to
benefit from but you're still doing the
work towards it because you know it
needs to be done yes definitely missing
now there's no like that's something
that is severely lacking in game a
because get game is about you know well
well the money if I'm gonna plant a tree
pay me yeah exactly
a tree and it's before we get started
there's I do want to give Brad a chance
to just speak up because I know he had
some issues in the first step so bright
if you want to give us a couple on your
project okay thanks for dealing with my
technical issues or being patient with
them so I'm Brad and I'm doing a friend
of Agriculture event in Columbus Ohio
and the past week I've been kind of
chopping up logs to get ready for
shiitake log cultivation so it's been
quite a exhausting process and fun at
the same time but that's kind of how my
weeks been just dealing with logs and
trying to get them in the right size and
right diameter so we can cultivate some
shiitake mushrooms cool like that's the
first time we've ever had that kind of a
project update yeah that's awesome
I suppose so you know I've been at my
keyboard all the time and yeah it's cool
to have a non like pure tech one where
it's actually like Oh someone's doing
stuff in the physical world let's go all
right good stuff should talk you much I
didn't know that those were cultivating
on laws yeah you can do them indoors on
sawdust or compost or some other medium
I've I've experimented with indoor
cultivation of blue oysters and lion's
mane and reishi mushrooms really don't
enjoy growing mushrooms indoors I hope
they did and then I have some concerns
my backgrounds in medical Dietetics and
I just had some concerns about the
hardiness of the mushrooms and having
medicinal benefits grown in such a
sterile environment and I'm finding I
like the outdoor nature of block
cultivation however there's a year lag
time between where you inoculate the
logs and where they're actually gonna
bear the fruit of the mushroom so you
can call them
they won't be ready until next year okay
is that one where like it's again the
term but where you sort of do the
cultivation once and just keep going
back to the same spot and getting new
mushrooms every year yes so it will
there's different like flushes that it
does so you'll be able to harvest it for
three to five years ongoing before our
potentially need new blogs but my wife
and I had a very big silver maple tree
growing right outside our door that was
growing into our foundation and
uprooting our patio and it needed to
come down so thankfully that is the type
of wood that you need for sake mushrooms
so making good use of the lumber cool
yeah that's actually extra cool to hear
that yeah it's being salvaged from
something that otherwise might have
nature if it's gone to be firewood or
something okay
all right I guess we can return to the
previous conversation on what my juice
needs help with oh then you just left
I'm sure you're a pro to work from home
stuff a lot of us just struggling with
the technology it I think some yeah I
beat echnology wasn't the issue for me
it was like this thing focused it was
you know I'm at home on you know my dog
is next to me I can go to the fridge I
can do whatever I want but I have to you
know stay on focus yeah I think I don't
know one of us probably weren't prepared
for for all this I know my webcam was
like twenty dollars that's why we're
having so many issues with it right yeah
I mean this has been that and we I've
also found the people that aren't used
to working from home like in the sort of
b2b gameid corporate environment
it's them who really want to like use
the video stuff and always do video
chats and my whole team is to disperse
and working from cities where there's no
office so that they're used to it and we
seldom have our cameras on because we're
just so used to it that it's we don't
sort of get that
fake in-person vibe that you get from
the the on camera can meeting this is
one of the few times a week that I do go
on camera nice
I had a separate conversation yesterday
was the game be coffee talk and
interesting topic came up that I I've
been really struggling with and I didn't
know if anyone else wanted to chime in
with their opinions or perspectives
essentially it was the dynamics between
game the discussions and what we
cultivate online as a general direction
and framework and then actually
implementing stuff in your own community
or city I feel like if you're not
incorporating people in your own
community or city and it could feel
really heavy-handed and top-down and
social engineered but at the same time
if you live in a commune like mine
they're not familiar with game B or game
a or they don't even have the time to
read philosophy or things like that
so it's a kind of a paradox that I don't
know how to settle this anyone have
anything to offer for that um there was
another project that was dealing with I
think Mike is intentionally trying to
build local sort of groups for possibly
things like this thing was called cult
culture creator that I'm not sure what
sort of work has been done it since then
but we had a a talk on that and sort of
ways to possibly generate like a local
audience I think that is one unique
thing about yours is tech projects I
really don't care if it's local or not
because as long as you know you have
internet and a computer you can sort of
use it and participate but yours I guess
is a bit different we can I have to in
theory have some sort of a setup and I I
imagine it helps to be local what when
you're talking about doing physical
things and showing it showing you like
hey here's how you know blogs and
harvest shiitake mushrooms and that kind
of me
I noticed this and this is a very big
thing and I think it's an underestimated
how big it is I talked to the zeitgeist
movement in my local country I'm Brown
branch of it at least and I know that
usually internet projects where you have
the zeitgeist movement as big and yet it
seems to exist mostly in in the cloud in
on the internet people talk about
philosophy and about economics and about
Jacque Fresco's ideas and there are
great ideas but then you have as you
said philosophy on one side and it's
great to talk about it but on the other
side you have local communities which
never heard of gave me Jacque fresco
like the Venus Project or anything like
that they just do the thing and it seems
there is no communication going between
like in either direction it's very hard
to you know we discussed actually
something like when you go to a local
community to spread your ideas about you
know resource-based economy what exactly
that is that you can say to the people
who are practicing it and how can you
like does it even make sense to go to
the people and spread to the ideas it
doesn't seem to work I think it makes
sense but it doesn't seem to work
because it looks like some kind of
evangelical you know hello I'm here to
talk about no higher being and and
people go like ok nice idea you have
there but what does it have to do is
what I am doing and the other right
direction is when you leave in local
community I'm not sure if it's your
observation as well on the world
you have in front of you and you don't
waste time on getting the feels of you
cut about it I'll do you right I think a
lot is have a numbers game personally
where I think it's like a small number
people will be you know the sort of
philosophical trying to solve letters at
that level and the internet just helps
them say we can you know coalesce
regardless where we are and share
information online
whereas with that physical work you kind
of can only do it in person and some
people that's just all they like and all
the day care about or at least you know
what will one of their higher priorities
is doing that kind of physical work
actually doing things completing things
you know something that you can hold
that you can say I made this exactly and
in my experience it does sort of tend to
be some people value one thing or
another the physical thing it's harder
to do online I guess maybe with 3d
printing and you know and modeling maybe
a bit but for the most part I think
that's part of the reason for that
separation but interested to hear what
others have to say am i right in
thinking that it's a paradox or am i
overthinking it because like I said one
participant yesterday was saying that
game be ish feels better or seems like
it's better when it's co-created and
co-evolved by the community members and
not imported from top-down but at the
same time you have to start somewhere in
a direction you wouldn't want to
cultivate a community going farther into
game a and doing more disastrous stuff
so to some extent it seems like you have
to push it in the direction and almost
cultivate a attractor
that's a greater than game a but at the
same time you don't want to be preaching
this is the way I don't you think it's a
paradox er again am i overthinking it
it's not about it looks like I
personally don't see to the paradox I
think we're missing a step I think we're
like trying continue to take something
from the conceptual from like okay we
have
all these great ideas how do we turn it
into something real and in my experience
that involved a different group of
people involved the people who like to
do things you'd like to create and I've
been noticing in the game be group you
can see those two groups you can see the
people who are like they have always
cool
you know like the these podcasts and
in-depth discussions and they're really
interesting to follow both but then
nothing like physical comes out of it
there's no product of it and then you
see people who post like you can tell
they just want to build something they
want to be a part of that they want to
actually go out and do and create and I
think that's one of the things that in
the game be projects group I think
that's one of the reasons why people
join because they're wanting to create
and I've seen probably at least that now
high posts of people like wanting that
kind of project tracker wanting to know
what what are all of these things they
possibly could help with or how they can
get help and personally I think we're a
bit too scared of game a tactics and
game a things until we figured out a
reliable game being way to do it if
there's no game be model to process
ourselves off of it it seems that
everyone is scared of like marketing and
advertising and as soon as you say that
that game a does it it seems like a lot
of people are like oh we can't do it
then even if I the only way that we know
how to right now and like a lot of stuff
with game a we did it because that's how
it works
marketing is an inherently game a it's
trying to understand the market and
people how do you have that kind of
unilateral conversation and that's a
part that I think a lot like I'm
definitely missing the ability to have
that say something that makes sense to a
group of people and inspire action I'm
terrible at that
but that's marketing I think that's one
of the things that we're missing is that
PlayBook to help turn the ideas into
things and III just said want to be a
truthful best we're scared the game is
up buddy right interested to hear what
others have to say I think about this
saying like for me community is way more
important
and yet I'm really disconnected from my
community I have I live in the country I
moved out here
and I'll just say the politics are
different here than where I'm from so
I've had a hard time connecting with
similar people and I've tried to do
things that help build community like I
tried to do an art project where I
thought we could create a commons just
for like a month or two where we could
get together and solve problems meet
each other do whatever and I came
against a lot of people work because I
put out flyers that said there's this
competition this project thing see if
you're interested people would come to
me and say like oh I you know you can't
expect the community to build your
business I'm like it's not a business
it's like a community center it's a
Commons and they're like well I've built
my business myself and I'm like actually
you have a hockey stand and you need me
to come and buy coffee from you or you
don't have a business so you didn't just
build it yourself so they were it was a
challenge I remember a lot of friction
and I'm not very good at introducing
ideas but I do think that you're right
you're right on what we're missing
it is like we need the game be systems
like the systemic structure which in my
mind my vision my pet project is that we
do have hubs or Commons areas for people
to connect in every community of seven
to 10,000 people that are like
legitimately a neutral space where
people come together with exactly all
these things that we're talking about
now but I think the whole game be
structure in my mind is a safety net so
like trying to show a way that it's
valuable to have this interconnectivity
it's a different it's different
obviously you know you're gave me people
um but having the actual structure in
place so people can come bring their own
interests and ideas and and meet people
to solve the problems locally but also
be able to share it globally and not be
in competition so it's kind I think this
is exactly where
trying to build this new thing and I
think it's very important that becomes
very grounded in community that every
community starts to have their own value
the resources that they see as
collective as Commons so they're all
invested like they can see that how
they're invested in the same system I
mean we can still function with game a
happening but I feel like once we start
having these structures in my mind we
have hubs everywhere across the world we
have our own multi-level value system
that's like decentralized so I'm in
control of my value system that's
connecting with all these people just to
like get that mapping out there see how
interconnected we are and then we don't
need top-down structures to fix our
problems we keep it together no I don't
know it's kind of a rant but I'm
thinking about those things too right I
think I might add to it as sometimes
people forget so they don't know because
they don't think about it that's the
basis for everything as relations
between people and it's not than just
relations between people but on top of
reactions between people you build
businesses and then you have this
imaginary structures as for-profit stuff
and companies and everything right but
it starts with person-to-person
communication even if it's communication
of the type I sell you listen to I give
you this and you give me money it's a
very particular and specific kind of
relation but it's a mistake to assume
that there is only this type of relation
which name I seems to be in like
preferring to think that between people
what exists is direct this relation of
exchange all the time exchanged and
usually is exchanged for money and
measuring everything in terms of money
when I moved to where I live now
and actually started having children I
found this community of people here
local people and they are involved in
NVC type of non-violent communication
which is approach to communication that
involves deeply thinking about what you
bring to the table and where your
thoughts and emotions come from and
understand understanding other people's
emotions and motivations and everything
it's very like deep sink when it's done
properly and it's amazing and it's very
really successful in terms of making the
relations deep and sustainable and like
I know I can always count on some people
around me and having this community
around us just it's a new quality of
life I have to say so we our communities
are great that's what I want to say make
sense and really if you think about sort
of a game a corporation they haven't a
massive amount of emphasis on internal
communication right like that's kind of
the main job of managers and executives
it's just aligning people and
communicating and making sure everyone's
going in the same direction
mm-hm where I mean we're seeing with the
whole quarantine thing that people
saying like well wait why do they care
if we go back to work if they're doing
it all themselves
oh is it cuz we do all the work Oh
interesting okay and it's cuz yeah
they're just arranging it which is still
valuable I think that goes to what
you're saying it's about that
relationship it's about sort of
conveying that information and using the
different types of people available and
yelled their different parodies intent
and skill sets to hopefully achieve the
same goal which again has to be
communicated I know one of the
challenges I find is like I lacked the
skill set which is a bit of the thing
where is that I'm not good at marketing
but it's
also the ability to properly explain
that kind of conceptual thing but the
person hearing it also has to have some
kind of a skill set or some kind of an
interest to understand it like I find
the same thing we're trying to explain
software like even if I've been doing it
for years I can be talking to a
developer that's done it for years
you're just trying to use words it
almost always fails you start to like
have a sketch like here's how it looks
that's where they're like okay I see
what you're saying now even if you're
both extremely technical until you can
see it and then you can hit oh well
maybe change that and do that it starts
to put everything in place even if they
don't agree it gives you that framework
to to build on and this sort of you know
both understand it instead of I say you
know a box pops up and there you know
envisioning something totally different
I think those two kind of had some
similarities trying to explain something
technical or something
hello Safa chol just trying to use words
is exceptionally hard to pass and then
again the other person has to understand
um so I did want to bring that back as
I'm not sure that we got any sort of
like an action or next steps for
Medusa's project before so you know
people to test it and to sort of help
move it along so I want to make sure
that we do get sort of some information
on that and see if we can actually okay
right now because I can just show it but
on the other hand I could populate it
with some data to be able to better show
it in a tomorrow with Sunday but early
next week
okay maybe it would make sense I mean uh
it's correct me if I'm wrong but from
the early meetings I understand that if
there's a project that could be
discussed we could as together attack
organize a meeting about this thing
right yeah it we can do a project
raising so if you have yeah we can get
together and it's a big similar to this
except the whole meeting is on a single
project where the person sort of says
hey here's what I'm trying to get out of
it here's the information about the
project and the other people will ask
questions give feedback that kind of
thing that would be most useful because
I know I was very good at communicating
ideas and it just might I'm not sure
what can be done in 20 minutes
especially if this meeting is small
general so it would be nice to organize
a specific meeting where I can be happy
to be grilled and try to do my best to
explain what it is I had in mind when I
started doing this okay sure yeah
if you need any help like if you're
trying to get it to the point where it's
ready to sort of get that early feedback
I'm happy to help like to take sort of
you know a sneak peek and maybe give
some feedback into where you can use
some sample information because I I have
the exact same challenge right I tried
to show off the current prototype didn't
have any information didn't make
it's still kind of early days and I feel
like I need even more example
information to really give somebody an
idea about what it's trying to
accomplish and so I think you might be
in the same spot it sounds like yeah I
concentrated concentrated on building
this framework and right now it's like
building a house and you have this the
walls and roof but there's nothing
inside so when you show it it's like
okay this is this and this is supposed
to be doing this end and it's much
easier to show it then to talk about it
yeah so I guess I need a day or two to
have some bugs the most obvious ones I
run out and get some data in so I can
better show what it is that needs to be
achieved right okay that make sense
cool thank you very much and Brad was
there anything that you needed help with
her need this chopping logs um bring out
shopping logs the kind of long-term
project that needs help on is more
around that packaging that we discussed
last week but I'm not in a place to kind
of research that myself at this time I
need to kind of get these logs going and
then when there's more of a long time I
I can kind of revisit the packaging
right okay um did you see the I want to
say solution raising next week on pepper
noon I did it's at once day and I be
working so fortunately I'm gonna be able
to make that but I'm sorry I actually
have some company that kind of came by
earlier than expected I have to jump off
so far technical issues and having to
leave or at least notice that's why all
right have it thank you take care wait
[Music]
all right there will be a good example
of how its of what is needed when
someone says okay I don't have time to
research companies but maybe someone
else has time there's no like expert
knowledge involved in packaging other is
maybe I don't know but simply to talk to
companies and to check if what processes
they use and whether they would be
willing to share how they do stuff and
just talk to people that takes time and
right now we do have time yeah I think
that was a part of the conversation
because I think as as Brad just said it
came out of a conversation last week
where he was talking about like how do I
have you know sort of all biodegradable
packaging that's where we gotten to the
help conversation and like could you you
know somehow turn kelp into something
that you could 3d print so that it was
stuff i degradable before and yeah that
got into a whole squirrel conversation
and then that stack might a bit but that
is kind of a part of the challenge with
solution raising and project raisings is
in theory there's some amount of
expertise involved that seldom people
involved have like I don't think anyone
actually attending that session has any
experience in packaging or even in
manufacture but they're still gonna have
a conversation because as you just said
they have time and it has to start
somewhere
but I think there is a yeah if there's
somebody available who has an expertise
we should definitely give them sort of
you know more voice than normal to say
like hey we're world here but that
person actually you know in theory knows
what they're talking about
so will air towards them one possible I
was very impressed by the Barbara shares
that talk which I looked
okay watch it right after last week's
meeting and what she said about you know
when you ask the question express a wish
wish and an obstacle there's always
someone in the crowd who knows the exact
answer so automatically I because that's
what I don't like thinking cold
sort of solution for this would be what
exactly on the internet you have a
webpage of system that you can put a
question or like one sentence I want to
this and I cannot do this because this
and when enough people sees this thing
someone who'd respond ideally right yeah
I I can see that being like so you know
almost a bit like Reddit but with a
specific tour purpose we're like there's
you would post I guess she quite a bit
favorite or you would post you know
somebody says I'm trying to solve X
problem and then if other people people
care about that problem they can you
know vote up and down to make it more
like people to see and then people can
you know just suggest solutions and
people can up down and you know up and
down both those solutions for those
problems and then that might be how we
sort of pick the topics or you know help
preload the solution raising
conversations with okay here's you know
a problem that people said was important
here's the top five solutions let's talk
about those and maybe some ones that the
community might have missed or you know
if we have an expert what they can chime
in for mm-hmm
try let's see
you unmuted and it go Alan make sure
that you're able to speak if you wants
to I did but I don't remember one way
more than I think master it might have
gone I was um after you guys had to talk
about packs her last week's talk it
wasn't really about packaging but
Brandon mentioned he was looking into
packaging I did look and see and they do
have hemp filament now for 3d printing
that might be a good this happens
becoming such a good product and it's
sustainable and it's gonna be really
available so that might be a good thing
for now yeah let's go at the end in fact
is I'm sure if you do a google search
for him 3d printing you'd find it I'm
very interested to see where three pip
pending ends up that's a really cool
technology did I think it's still in its
infancy compared to where we're gonna
see it in 10 20 years yeah there's a
great potential for this and it's such a
shame that Hank got this bad reputation
yes obviously in Poland we used to I
will stop we used to have many many
years ago like plantations of and in the
medieval times
I think I might be wrong it was used for
everything because it's such a great
plant and the fabric made of stuff is
great and hemp concrete yeah and like
you know it can be healthy for you it
can be it can be hard to not grow it
like it's a weed right in there things
like it's actually quite hard like it's
yeah it's kind of is the perfect plant
and it's bizarre uh I mean there's you
know ten different or a lot more than 10
different conspiracy theories as to why
it was banned and who was behind it but
he may capitalism in the end I think
that was just the tool they used it well
at least for half of the conspiracy
theories it sounds like that was just
you know they were able to do it in that
way but yeah doable either stepped on
somebody's to
or some sort of racist overtones or the
two that offered any way that you could
come things some industry wanted a gun
or you know just cuz Hampton sort of the
world heads-up like the cousin of
marijuana but because they're you know
sort of in the same basket but should
ban all of it that's that was the
official explanation a friend of mine
who wanted to grow like a very small
field off and for think four which is
weird because centuries ago we had like
full fields of the stuff and to just
using it so now experiment we this
sounds like weird thing but still she
had to get like specific official
permission for just summing this view
and then the police came in and I think
they burnt it the order is to be burned
because it's helped so you permission
you look you have the permission doesn't
matter just burn it because yeah you
know the permission is still burned it
yes that's the way it looks here
so and especially now when you see
people being beaten up by the police
because they go outside because of the
virus and that's the situation is crazy
and it's very great situation to breed
some of POC series yeah they really
haven't been handling that part well at
all no no III mean I think a few select
governments have had doing okay but as a
whole it shows how ridiculous this does
this well everything else we need the
better system
I'll have to call it a trust vacuum the
the issue that right now because there's
no single guide like people to across
the media people Don trust the
government's and some people trust
experts but if there's five experts
trotted out and they all disagree with
each other who do you listen to yeah
not the time for but unfortunately
that's what appears to be the thing
that's going to highlight the issues so
just one quick thing that the hemp
growing I have noticed that there are a
lot of laws changing and especially in
the US where we're letting you have to
get permitted or whatever to grow but
there's a lot more kept growing and like
you're talking about that hempcrete the
concrete is hurting to use it in
building supplies I think it is gonna be
a really big industry and I was just
recently on a couple calls solution
calls with another group I'm in and some
people in California that are using
carbon tax credits to fund growing their
hemp because it's actually encapsulating
apartment right cool even they're like
getting Native Americans to not really
donate their land but let them lease the
land they go to yeah so there's some
interesting twists happening with that
very cool yeah I've heard that
um who is it Levi's has started to use
hemp in their jeans again hey so yeah
it's starting to oh yeah it was like
it's an amazing fabric yeah and like
quite possibly the best one we have like
where it's really sustainable super
tough like yeah I mean maybe not for
like luxurious you know silk items maybe
hem stuff but for most things like it
can yeah that's that that's green jeans
cool neck condition there's a branding
opportunity there
[Laughter]
cool all right we're down to the last
five minutes I don't know if anyone has
any final thoughts before we wrap up I
will say I think that theme of like that
I don't know frustration is too strong
of a word but that frustration over the
disconnect between like the philosophy
of game being and actually trying to do
stuff I know I think both sides seem to
be frustrated with that disconnect be
between those two groups because they
don't tend to overlap that much in my
experience and there is it's like the
two islands we yeah and this bit of sea
between the islands is like you still
see ships going between and some
communication happening but it looks
like you know throwing grenades of
throwing ideas and the land or not and
it's immature so we need a breach
definitely some sort of and again this
is what I've been thinking about since
very long time ago reach consisting of a
place a platform where it is possible to
have status as close to physical things
as possible and this would be
documentation and project management is
also involved English and blueprints of
like for example the echo of the side
that has blueprints for basic tools that
you can use to build your own village
they have this and this is great because
it connects physical world to the world
of ideas because you have tools which is
physical you have the documentation and
some written stuff about new tools and
then you
and have some philosophy thrown in like
trying to be not very suspicious just
you know stick in some philosophy why
exactly it is we need the documentation
for tools and why we need the tools and
it's not just go to the shop and buy
them so there's some potential in such a
platform to arrive oh yeah I think
that's one of the goals of together tech
that's kind of something that's trying
to be is is at least in my mind a
project is how you take something from
idea to you know you eat it physical or
if it's a digital product you know to
put online that's the process and that's
a really vague term like the process
from taking out an idea to making it but
projects can be kind of a they go
through different phases of it's still
pretty conceptual let's figure out how
we're gonna make this - all right it's
half built where do we go next
yes mmm it's like when you think about
different oh it goes back to like oh I
think and you have some physical
something like and it's physical but at
the same time there was oh I cannot
refuse of he really but there is an idea
behind it right so you have the Magnus
ver Magnusson which is embodied in this
but from the idea to this there is this
process of manufacturing and a lot of
stuff really like conceptual and lots of
words between the idea and we used
really I think part of the challenge is
if we're talking about you know trying
to make mugs well the idea of a mug
that's not new so if you're trying to
make mugs in do you want to hire people
you can say hey make this but instead of
that design I want you know dogs or
whatever it is you might have a slightly
different idea but it's generally the
same then people can understand
and go make it but if you a brand new
idea that's never been made that's a
bridge that you have to cross first you
have to make sure that the people that
you want to first hire and then be
actually trained ahead and is work it to
understand what they're making and that
generally like starts even hiring or
getting them involved because they have
to understand what they're doing and
that can be step one is taking that idea
exploiting it enough that somebody wants
to get involved to actually help you
make it and that I think are yet
absolutely worth like that's my
challenge now it is trying to explain
that that idea cuz there's nothing like
this as far as I know so having that up
trying to explain it well enough to get
some of the interest it's but they can
help build something that isn't fully
hashed out
there's a great chance you see local
people and ok I want to be this
understand this and they go why right is
good enough what probably trying to
solve what what did the mug not do for
you exactly and a lot like there's the
old Henry Ford saying where it's you
know if ask people what they wanted they
just buh-buh-buh-buh-buh and set a
faster horse yes mm-hmm
right and it's I mean and it kind of the
same thing like with the iPhone and
everything else if you know you ask
people for a better phone oh maybe you
know a better this and better that Bowl
touchscreen you're crazy and they've
passed for 10 years what the hell is a
non-smart phone what do you look like
it's no one is going to use that no idea
that was really hard to comprehend at
birth and to be like that's never going
to work and then people doing it we saw
it we started to understand it that
moved it forward and a bit easier to
iterate iterate iterate an hour where we
are now now in place suddenly you find
yourself unable to live without this
would you five years ago it's think like
well why that's why it's funny to look
read quotes from famous CEOs and
industry people about computers like
from 20 30 50 years ago
yeah there's the these super popular
numbers like there's a world market for
maybe 50 computers yes Wow that one did
not any but I love what you guys both
just said and I feel well as an artist I
have to do exactly what you're talking
about maybe art is a good bridge between
these you know getting it out there and
what not even like I started out when I
learned how to make love let's say a cup
there's a huge learning curve and you
might think just cuz we've already made
them that they're easy it seems like and
there are concerns manufacturing ways to
do it without your hands aren't involved
but all open you're actually learning a
new skill it takes a lot of time and
after a while you get really bored with
that one style and you start doing
different things but you don't really
you can't know that until you're
actually physically doing it so also
being an artist like my dream is to take
my art have an art show that's open to
the public and introduce these kind of
ideas to them through our s just a
entrance point so that their mind is a
little bit more expansive and when
you're in an art studio or an art show
you kind of you imagine be impossible or
at least you try to write well maybe um
well that's my goal
kind of I think you're what do you guys
think yeah because I artists are more
comfortable in the conceptual and I
experience and it might take you a bit
to align those concepts but you're
probably going to have a more and if
they don't get it they're probably going
to be better at sketching where they're
at like okay is this what you need no
okay is this what you mean a bit closer
okay is this what you mean until you're
at the point or yeah that's what I mean
cool and then you figure out how that
sometimes you don't know like you're
making art and you don't know the end
but you're in the process and you keep
going and going to going until there is
an end which is really about that trust
you're talking about a lot of people
don't have that that's hard to grasp in
our regular world where everything we
just buy everything we don't have a lot
of
oh they spring it up the house Ullom
what wrong yeah or return or they've a
bad Yelp reviewer right whatever you
know what whatever animal would we have
in a chamber at that time but I also
like I personally debts like as soon as
you said that I'm like yeah that makes
100% sense because right now the stage
I'm in and trying to explain wiki
election before it's coated is basically
art it's infographics its charts it's
this trying to take that concept and
explain it without actually having it
built which I mean it's not nice art but
it smart I don't so ya know I think that
makes oh it's one of the things I like
very much about son art Bank community
I'm not sure if you are familiar with
this but okay cyberpunk
is Tiger Punk is it's very gloomy dark
industrious and stop young like image of
the future solar pump is the opposite I
know it looks at the future as being
bright and colorful and a big part of it
imagine how you look like
and it's very green colorful and arty
beautiful solar punk solar so that's it
like the Sun yes oh oh yeah it's awesome
because it's very utopian as such but it
shows that a much better future is
definitely possible and this is the
future where we don't go in like totally
cybernetic direction of you know
computers and technology and not going
back to the medieval times we have
technology because first it's not
possible and second every time I hear
someone talking about how good it was
hundred years ago no it wasn't it was
totally at least we didn't have
computers so yeah oh baby effectively
the only people that should ever really
say that or probably white men some
countries that and overall and even then
yeah like 200 years ago where to fight
me I guess if you're in the u.s. it's it
wasn't when I read history books about
that period no no no and when someone
says okay I it would be nice to live in
go back to the beautiful types of nature
and you know peace as no there was no
peaceful nature it's not what you think
it is right so yeah but we kind of
mixing technology with nature and in the
graceful way in a very subtle way so you
have nature and very respect for nature
and what goes inside is also like
Dharmakara culture like growing
beautiful gardens and you know caring
about cameras a bit like it's just the
emphasis on the end result if they take
technology to get there great if we can
do it naturally great but it's not just
like technology for technology's sake
exactly
which you know is kind of or technology
for profit sick which just means making
it as much as possible you know
quick quick iterations maybe it doesn't
last that long the opposite of all that
it's much better when it doesn't last
long because then you can sell another
yeah
in-game a totally yeah you know why they
do that now right because did that part
where like they don't build them like
they used to in some cases that's true
in some cases they're there's reasons
but in a lot of things it's yeah just so
that
you have to buy more first heard about
planned obsolescence that's yeah it was
like it was enlightening and at the same
time we are so much in trouble
only in invent it's like planned
obsolescence that's just crazy
yeah well I mean one of the things that
we have to do in the next 50 or 100
years I mean probably even sooner than
that is figure out a way to start to
reclaim those materials because
otherwise are gonna be like we're kind
of starting to run out of gold and
silver guys all right let's you know I
don't know make some nanites to go
through garbage dumpsters or or
something but some way to reclaim it
because otherwise I mean you know most
of our stuff is going to be in the
trans-pacific Garbage Patch yeah we have
going to see new animal species just you
know of trash which I heard already
happening a little shrimp whatever it
was with plastic embedded in and I'm
sure if it was like evolved okay I don't
know but they they found mushrooms that
can actually like eat plastic so you
don't have to eat it but they don't like
it turns into not plastic cuz Oh
everything is eating plastic that's part
of the problem is it doesn't turn into
something that's not plastic so we've
all got plastic yeah I think there's
there's mushrooms and I want to say
worms or some kind of bug it may
actually been shrimp that they've also
found can eat it and then they've also
found mushrooms that can I don't know if
eat is the right term but like consume
and nullify radiation okay didn't find
the ethereal internal or their like it
seemed to be absorbing it like changing
it this is like they've never seen that
before yeah in the last five years I
think they found two mushrooms that are
like potentially solving some pretty
major issues thank you
nature is great I mean if you don't have
to leave 200 years ago and struggle with
it
if you but it's got to understand yet
nature it's
it's as hard as understanding complex
systems it's a totally different game
but yeah nature's amazing and if used
properly is understood a if cooperated
with properly I think operation is the
right order
yeah I mean it is interesting just how
many things are happening right now
where it seems like nature might be a
little bit fed up but even aside from
the kernel arts thing I heard there's
some state in the US where they have two
category five tornadoes at the same time
like Earth's the same well some people
will say yeah Gaia is waking up and okay
you must you have your chance
no thank you I think it's just you know
it's a nice soft check being like by the
way mm-hmm things can you know change
pretty quickly so here's your warning
that's been a really interesting thing
is like after all the emphasis on
climate change now that like people
aren't we're talking about it but but
but be forced to stay inside like it's
actually all of a sudden starting to get
way better 20 20 about climate change
but cool all right yes we should
probably end this dreamwalk quite a bit
over any final thoughts before we end
stream and we could stick around after
you want to keep chatting with us so
that the stream is in two hours mm-hmm
needs to feed my kids all right thank
you